TEN (ENVELOPE)
[narrator] Ten:
The ability to envelop your body
in a shroud of Nen aura,
making it tougher
and slowing the effects of aging.
ZETSU (SUPPRESS)
Zetsu:
A technique which shuts off
your flow of Nen aura.
Effective for concealing your presence
and recovering from fatigue.
REN (REFINE)
Ren.
A technique for creating
an especially strong Nen aura.
It is crucial for increasing your power.
HATSU (RELEASE)
Hatsu:
The release of your Nen aura,
after using Ren to boost it.
These four elements
are known as the Four Exercises
and are critical to the mastery of Nen.
FOUR EXERCISES
[theme song playing]
[cheering]
Oh...
[Hisoka] Oh… Don’t look at me like that…
SCHWEEN
It’s really turning me on!
A BIG DEBT x AND x A SMALL KICK
[narrator] Gon was finally able to land
a solid punch to Hisoka’s face.
But will he be able to win the match?
Critical hit for Gon! Two points!
[Cocco] Amazing!
Gon managed to land a critical hit!
He’s come back from a deficit
to take a two-one lead.
Gon is on top!
But wait a second!
Hisoka looks just fine.
In fact, it doesn’t like he took on
very much damage at all!
The referee’s call
might be open to question!
The referee is perfectly entitled
to award points however he pleases.
Huh?
As you’re aware some award points
based on damage done
while others base their scores
on strategy and technique.
My personal opinion is that,
in this case
the referee was rewarding the fighter
for using the stone block in his attack.
Oh, is that so?
And… who are you?
Okay!
[cheering]
[Cocco] Oh, look at that!
Hisoka has moved for the first time
since the fight started.
And is that a hint of a smile I see?
Can this mean
that he’s finally getting serious?
Whoa!
Whoa! What was that all about?
I have no idea!
One question:
How much have you learned about Nen?
I know all the basics.
[Hisoka] Ah.
That means you’re an Enhancer.
[Gon]
Uh... But… how the hell did you know that?
[chuckles]
[Hisoka] You're so adorable
and not very good at keeping secrets,
are you?
[Gon growls]
Shut your big mouth!
Just tell me how you knew!
It’s personality analysis
based on aura type.
It’s not an exact science…
much like personality profiles
based only on blood type.
Enhancers are simple and determined!
He’s right!
Oh, and am a Transmuter, by the way.
Both whimsical and a liar!
He’s right!
Emitters are short-tempered.
Specialists tend to be independent.
Conjurers are high-strung and nervous.
Manipulators are argumentative.
We’re quite compatible, you and I.
Our opposing personalities attract.
We could become great friends…
But I’d be careful if I were you,
as Transmuters are known to be fickle.
What was once treasured
can easily become trash.
[Hisoka] So...
I really hope you don’t disappoint me.
Gon.
-[Gon grunts]
-[audience roars]
He's fast!
[Gon grunts]
[audience roaring]
[Cocco] That was one powerful kick!
He sent that stone tile
flying all the way to the entrance!
[Gon grunts]
[cries out in pain]
[rasping in pain, determined growl]
[tired exhale]
[Cocco] Look at that speed, folks!
Hisoka is showing his true power!
Critical hit Hisoka.
Bringing the score to three-two!
[Cocco] His nonstop flurry of attacks
has been scored a critical hit
and Hisoka regains the lead!
[Gon panting]
[Cocco]
Gon looks confused and is backing off.
Can’t he fight back?
Amazing…
Too amazing!
[Hisoka] What’s wrong?
Come on, attack me.
Don’t wanna. I’m thinking!
[panting]
I can barely follow him with my eyes
and the rest of my body
just can’t keep up!
At this rate,
he’ll beat the crap out of me!
[Hisoka] Hmmm… Very well.
If you won’t come willingly,
I suppose I’ll have to force you.
You’ve gotta use Gyo!
Dammit!
[focusing grunt]
Do you even have the slightest idea
what’s about to happen?
[straining]
[screaming]
[Cocco] Whoa! Look at that!
Gon is being drawn toward Hisoka!
[rasping in pain]
This is my “Elastic Love”…
better known as Bungee Gum.
It can expand as well as contract…
attach and detach
as I desire
[grunts in pain]
You will never escape me now.
[cheering]
Critical hit and knockdown!
Three points awarded to Hisoka!
Six to two!
[groaning]
[Cocco] Hisoka clobbers Gon
with a strong right!
And Gon is down!
His aura turns into a rubbery substance
that attaches to other objects.
Bungee Gum.
Only Hisoka can attach and detach it.
What are you doing?
Stand up, Gon.
Dammit…
It’s six to two!
Hisoka has widened his lead even more!
Is he about to claim yet another victory
in his undefeated streak?
Hey! Get up, kid!
Come on, ref!
You’re totally favoring Hisoka!
You can do it, Gon!
Can you fight?
Of course!
[Cocco] Ohh, Gon is back on his feet!
But you can tell
he’s really taken a beating out there!
Now here’s a question for you…
[Gon] Huh?
And if you answer it correctly,
I’ll give you a free hit.
You will?
At what point during this match
did I attach my Bungee Gum to your cheek?
When did he attach it…?
One: When I elbowed you.
Two: When I landed a clean hit.
Three: When I landed the critical hit.
When was it?!
Number three!
It was when you hit me with both hands!
Wrong!
The answer is four.
It was actually when I was giving you
my aura personality analysis.
No fair!
[Gon] Damn!
If only I’d been using Gyo
from the very beginning…
Hmm...
Ah, yes.
One word of caution.
Had you been using Gyo,
then during my aura personality analysis,
you would have been able
to see exactly
what my aura was doing the entire time
and avoided it quite easily.
But what about situations
one, two, and three?
Have you figured it out?
I could also have attached my Bungee Gum
to you while attacking you directly.
You only need to conceal your aura
when you wish
to catch your opponent off guard.
Normally, you use your aura
when attacking.
It doesn’t really matter
if your opponent can see your aura
while you’re landing attacks.
He's right.
If I can’t dodge his attacks,
using Gyo to see his aura
won’t do me any good at all!
This is bad.
His power’s way more dangerous
than I thought it’d be!
So, you’ve gotta dodge
all of Hisoka’s attacks.
That’s the only way
that you’re ever gonna keep him
from attaching Bungee Gum to you.
But if you’re able to defend…
Defense wouldn’t be effective.
He can attach his aura
to the part you block with.
[sighs]
I can’t escape…
What should I do?
That’s enough talk for the time being.
Now what do you say
we begin preparing for battle?
Resume.
[moans]
If I can’t escape…
I’ll go forward!
[ecstatic moan] Gon…
Gon!
That’s good…
You’re so very good!
Those eyes…
That look…
That spirit!
[ecstatic moan]
[ecstatic moan] I just can’t wait...
to break you.
[roaring]
[Hisoka] Oh… but no. Not yet…
[Hisoka grunts]
[Cocco] Whoa!
[Hisoka] More… More!
[Hisoka]
Until it’s almost a shame to destroy you.
[Cocco] Ooh! That’s gotta hurt!
[Hisoka] Until you’ve matured…
[Cocco] Look at him go, folks!
[Hisoka] Until you’ve reached
soaring new heights…
[grunts] Patience…
[Cocco] A vicious assault!
[moans]
[Gon groans]
[Cocco] Oh! Not again!
[Gon groans in pain]
[Cocco] Hisoka draws Gon
right into another epic left uppercut!
Good! I blocked that one!
I’m getting used to his Bungee Gum
yanking me around all over the place.
But it’s not over.
Not yet!
I’m scared.
But I can’t let my fear take over.
If I do,
I’ll never be able
to fight anyone else again!
Both critical hits!
That’s two more points!
-Plus, a knockdown for Hisoka!
-Huh?
That’s nine points for Hisoka
and four points for Gon!
[Gon] But he never knocked me down!
And I even blocked his attack!
-What?
-Something is up with this ref!
Gimme a break, ref! Get your eyes checked!
Ooookay…
We have yet another interesting call.
The crowd’s not pleased
with the ref’s decision,
and they’re really letting him hear it!
[referee] Fight!
If he gets ten points, I lose.
I only have one point left…
He doesn’t need a knockdown.
If just one more attack hits me,
it’s over!
[chuckles]
You should be more vigilant, Gon.
Take a look over to the right.
I’m so sorry.
I suppose what I meant to say
was my right.
And that’s another knockdown
and a clean hit!
Two more points awarded!
Eleven to four!
The winner by TKO is…
Hisoka!
Huh?
[Wing sighs]
[relieved exhale]
While you were busy pleading
your case to the referee,
I sent the aura on my left hand
to the stone.
That’s nine points for Hisoka
and four points for Gon!
When I saw my opening,
I activated the Bungee Gum.
Huh? It’s really… over?
[Hisoka] You’ve made progress.
But you do still lack experience.
If we had ten more matches,
I believe we might actually
have a good fight.
Of course, that’s assuming
those fights take place here,
in Heavens Arena.
Therefore,
I will not be fighting you here again.
Our next fight will be in the real world,
without rules to hinder us.
With our lives on the line.
[Gon] He’s so far beyond me.
But he’s not so far out of reach
I can’t catch up someday.
I need more training in Nen.
I’ve gotta find a power
that’s as strong as Hisoka’s!
[Cocco] This victory marks
ten wins for Hisoka,
and earns him the right
to challenge a Floor Master!
Gon fought bravely,
and we wish him luck in his next match.
Well, that’s all for now, folks!
This is your commentator Cocco,
signing off!
A referee is supposed to be impartial.
But with this matchup
I thought it was prudent
to try and finish the fight quickly,
even if that meant
that I had to lower my standards.
[spectator 1] So he’s a technical judge.
[spectator 2] What does that mean?
[spectator 1] See, if a ref thinks
a fight is gonna get too dangerous,
he’ll award points like crazy
to try to get it over with fast.
Oh yeah?
Yeah, it’s something you gotta think about
when you’re placing a bet.
Ah, man!
I was sure Hisoka
was gonna win ten-nothin’!
About your fight with Hisoka…
There’s nothing I can tell you.
You understand better than anyone,
having faced him yourself.
“Understand”?
What he learned during that fight
of course.
Right!
What... exactly did you learn?
It’s secret!
[scoffs]
[Wing] Gon. Killua.
As you continue on your paths,
it will become ever more important
to master your very own styles of Nen.
-Yes!
-Yeah.
I’m really glad I got the chance
to meet both of you.
I look forward to training hard,
so I can surpass you one day.
You really think you can surpass us?
I promise you I will!
Not gonna happen.
Can’t wait to see you do it, Zushi!
Osu! [laughs]
-[Killua] Well, let's go.
-[Gon] 'kay.
Bye, Mister Wing!
And thank you for everything!
Yeah. Thanks a lot
for all your help, Wing.
You boys take care of yourselves!
[Gon] Bye, Zushi! See you later!
Osu!
[Killua] Well… you finally accomplished
your goal huh, Gon?
[Gon] Yep!
[Killua] No reason
for us to stick around anymore, then.
So… what are you gonna do next?
[Gon] I’m going back to Whale Island.
[Killua] Whale Island?
Yeah.
Since I was able
to “pay back” Hisoka,
I want to go back home
and finally show Aunt Mito
my Hunter’s License.
It’s crazy.
I haven’t been home in over six months.
-[Killua] I guess I'll come with you.
-Huh?
Yeah, I really want to meet Aunt Mito.
[Gon] You do? Then let’s go together!
[Killua] Sure. I’ll just tag along.
[Gon] Bye-bye… Heavens Arena.
[narrator] Gon fulfilled his promise
to punch Hisoka
and return his badge to him.
Despite losing the fight,
Gon was satisfied that he had achieved
his goal at long last.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Coming up:
-Gon...
-[Killua] ...and Killua’s…
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I’m Gon!
-I’m Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today, we're introducing--
-Gon!
-Who, me?
Gon became my very first friend
when we met at the Hunter Exam.
He's fun to be around
because his expressions
are always changing.
And you never know what he’s thinking.
[chuckles]
[Gon] Next time: “Ging x And x Gon”!
Hey! Wanna come to my house, Killua?
[Killua] I-- I’m not v-- very useful b--
but t-- thanks for letting me stay over!
[Gon] You're stuttering.